Welcome to season three
of 13 Reasons Why.
If you've been watching.
you know our show portrays a number
of real issues facing teenagers today.
We tell stories about things
like substance abuse.
bullying. sexual assault.
violence and suicide.
If these issues are in your life.
this series may not be right for you.
Or you may not want to watch it alone.
So. watch with your parents.
your family or your friends.
Then talk to someone about what you see...
What you think about it.
How it makes you feel.
And if you find you need help.
talk to a trusted adult.
Like a school counselor.
Or call a local helpline
or visit our website
at 13ReasonsWhy.info.
Once you start talking about it.
it gets better.
Enjoy the show.
Enjoy the conversation.
And take care of each other.
[theme music playing]
My name is Amorowat Anysia Achola.
You can call me Ani.
I'm a senior at Liberty High School.
You were lying to me the whole time.
[Bryce] Goddammit. Ani. I need you!
I need you so fucking bad.
[woman] Amorowat?
[Ani] My mum's a home health care worker.
We just got to Evergreen last spring.
April.
[Ani] Right. I'm off then.
[Ani's mum] Wait...
This is fashion?
It is quite stylish. yes. Thank you.
- The things that school allows.
- You don't even know.
I didn't see you all weekend.
I had both days off.
I had projects.
Next Sunday. I'll go to church with you.
- Yes?
- At the very least.
["Regret" playing]
[Ani] I just started at Liberty in April.
About eight months ago.
Yeah. I'm the new girl.
Do I like Liberty?
Sure.
It's an... interesting place.
Stuff happens at Liberty High School.
you know?
♪ I would like a place I can call my own ♪
♪ Have a conversation on the telephone ♪
[Ani] I'm guessing that's why I'm here.
♪ I would not complain
Of my wounded heart ♪
[Ani] You think I know something
about what happened?
Well. I do.
♪ I would like a place
I could call my own ♪
♪ Have a conversation on the telephone ♪
[Ani] I'm sure you got pieces
from other people.
♪ I would not complain
Of my wounded heart ♪
I can help you put them together.
[song fades]
[Ani] Jess...
If you're gonna apologize
about the homecoming game...
The police took Clay.
- What?
- Just now. I saw them out front.
Shit! Why now?
It's November.
Spring Fling was last April.
And why Clay?
[police radio] All units in the vicinity
of Mission and Twelfth.
assault in progress.
1705 Mission. Please respond.
Wanna get that?
- I'll take him back to the station.
- Right.
Dispatch. Unit 12 is responding.
Unit 4 returning to station.
[police radio]
683. that's one. seven. zero...
[police siren]
[tires screeching]
[sirens]
[Ani] There are things
I'm sure no one has told you.
Secrets that have been well-kept.
And yes. the keeper of those secrets
is often Clay Jensen.
[engine starting]
[cell phone vibrating]
Do you mind?
[Ani] One secret goes back to last spring.
- What the hell do you want. Jess?
- The cops took Clay.
They perp-walked him out of school.
Ani saw just now.
Shit!
Do you think they know...
about...
- Tyler?
- Do you think so?
- Did you tell them?
- [scoffs] Are you fucking serious?
- No. of course I didn't tell them.
- Really? 'Cause...
you've been pretty hostile
to everyone lately.
No. I've been pretty hostile
to you lately.
Plus this whole Tyler thing happened
seven months ago.
- Why would I say anything now?
- Why else would they want Clay?
- How would I know?
- Did something happen this weekend?
What did you do
after the homecoming game?
Not very damn much.
[bell rings]
- Zach.
- I...
have to go to history.
[Ani] These kids were connected
by their secrets.
Connected and forever changed.
[Alex] Here. I'll help you with that.
in terms of ironic things happening.
Not my first time on crutches. Alex.
- C'mon. Zach. give me a win.
- [Jess] Alex?
The cops were just here.
- They took Clay in.
- Okay.
- Okay?
- Yeah. I mean.
Clay's not gonna say anything
about anybody.
- Jess. come on.
- I have to go.
What's up with her? Hasn't it been
a few months since you guys...
Yeah. I guess it's a quick slide
from "we can be friends"
to "don't fucking touch me."
Your knee seems worse today.
Friday night you could put some weight
on it. right? Without the crutches?
Yeah. I mean...
that's how these things go.
It swells up.
Your eye's looking worse.
Yeah. that's the problem
with fighting football players.
it's like they... they have helmets.
[Ani] Even the ones
that don't like each other that much.
there's a bond.
They show up for each other.
- Good morning.
- The cops took Clay.
This morning. right outta school.
The sheriffs?
Javi. I gotta take care of something
for an hour or two.
- [Javi] Esta bien.
- You can't go down there.
You got a better idea?
You can't go down there.
It's not a good idea for you. I'll go.
You go down there. That's a better idea.
- What about the guns?
- That's dealt with. You know that.
No. all I know is you and Clay said
you took care of it.
It's best that's all you know.
[cell phone vibrating]
[Ani] So. yeah. The story begins
back in April.
I mean. if we're going to understand
how we got here.
I'll be there in two minutes.
I'm free and clear.
I don't even think they looked
as I drove by.
Yeah. Justin and those guys
are gonna talk to the police.
We got a story.
We didn't take it as real.
It's just him. you know?
I heard him talking about it
and I jumped to conclusions.
- It was a total joke. all right?
- [man] Yeah?
It was fucking stupid
but it was a total joke.
- [Standall] You made a joke?
- I did.
[Tony] Tyler? How you doing?
Just breathe. man.
Everything's going to be okay.
[police sirens]
Wait. they're... They're not coming here.
They're going to the school.
But we need you
to get out of the backpack
and the belt.
I need you to be here... with me.
- No. don't touch me!
- Okay!
- Don't fucking touch me!
- Okay. Tyler! I'm not.
I'm over here. You're good.
But I'm gonna need you
to take off the backpack
and take off the belt
and walk away from them.
[Tony] Now walk towards me.
It's just Clay.
It's just Clay. see?
I told you we were going to meet up
with him in the car.
Right. Okay.
[Clay] Hey. Tyler.
How you doing?
Shall we get you home?
[Tyler] Oh. my God...
My parents...
Tyler...
[Clay] What did you do?
[Ani] I don't know everything
that's happened since that night.
but I know it was Bryce Walker's
last night at Liberty.
And I'm the new kid. right?
I watch. I listen.
I know quite a bit.
And I'll tell you everything.
Do I need a lawyer?
[laughs] Oh... No.
No. this isn't any kind
of criminal investigation.
And you're over 18 now. right?
As of last month.
Yeah. so you don't even
need a parent here.
I mean. feel free to call your mom
if you want.
No. Thank you.
So. how are things at Liberty lately?
Fine. I guess.
Pretty stressful though. I imagine.
with everything that's going on.
Hannah's trial. then Bryce.
Then the false alarm
at the dance last spring.
now all this at Homecoming.
More than any one high school deserves.
I think a lot of high schools
go through a lot worse.
You're right.
But this thing with Homecoming...
were you there?
At the game Friday night?
I was.
Did you get caught up in it?
Not so much. A little.
Did you run into Bryce Walker?
We said hello.
Okay. Was this before the game or after?
Before.
Why?
Well...
[sighing]
See. the thing is. Clay...
Bryce was playing for Hillcrest
on Friday night.
He walked off the field
and hasn't been seen since.
Do you have any idea where he could be
or who he could be with?
[stammers] I don't.
Hmm.
Except for...
we found this...
inside Bryce's room.
You recognize that?
- [stammers] It used to be mine.
- You have any idea
how Bryce could come to have it
or why would it be in his room?
I don't know.
When's the last time you saw it
or had it in your possession?
[stammers] I don't remember.
I don't ride a bike anymore.
Okay.
Um...
Clay. you were seen
outside of Bryce's house
a few days before the homecoming game.
You apparently threatened him.
Specifically you said.
"I'll fucking kill you."
Can you explain that?
Who told you that?
It's not important.
Do you remember saying that?
I was... I was checking on a friend.
their safety.
I mean. Bryce has a history.
- [male teacher]...a triangle...
- [cell phone vibrating]
...by repeatedly removing
the middle triangle
from each of the prior generations.
the number of colored triangles increases
by a factor of...?
Triangle recursion by a factor of three.
- Mr. Wood?
- [Mr. Wood] Yes?
Would it be possible for me to run
to the robotics room for a few?
I've just realized
I've left a battery overcharging
and it's going to fry the motherboard.
Not a problem. I doubt
you need this review in the first place.
Well. I wasn't going to say anything.
but thank you.
Is there anything else
you think I should know?
No.
[knock on door]
All right.
I got to go check on a few things.
Be back in a couple of minutes.
Feel free to use your cell phone.
[door closing]
Clay. my name is Nora Walker.
Yes. I know... I know who you are.
[sighing]
Clay. I know Bryce hurt you
and friends of yours.
He's done some monstrous things.
But he's my son.
I don't excuse anything that he's done.
but he's my child.
And he might be lost.
He might be hurt.
Do you know anything
that might help us find him?
I don't. Mrs. Walker.
I'm sorry.
[Ani] Though to tell the truth.
I don't really know Clay Jensen
all that well.
He was a classmate.
Why am I not surprised you're here?
Was it about Tyler?
Not here.
[Ani] Do I think he's capable
of being violent?
I don't know. Do any of us really know
what we're capable of?
I have to tell the group text
it wasn't about Tyler.
As I'm not on that group.
are you gonna send me a separate text
as to what it was about.
or should I ask Justin or someone?
You're telling me you don't know?
Bryce is missing. He hasn't been seen
since Homecoming Friday night.
It didn't come up at home?
Well. my mum had the weekend off
and I made myself scarce.
as you might expect.
They think something happened to him.
that someone did something to him.
and they think the someone is me.
- Sweet Jesus.
- Yeah.
Prayers welcome.
[Ani] Does Clay have influence
over his peers?
I don't know.
I mean. he's not like...
the captain of the football team.
Come on. Charlie. Hustle.
You got beat on Friday.
Nah. you got beat on Friday!
I just sucked.
You're late.
- [Zach] With the DBs. other end zone.
- Okay.
[Zach] Where were you?
Were you with Clay?
I went to tell Tony.
Ani went to the station.
She thought it'd be best
if we just stay away.
We're fucked. right?
We're fucked.
We're not fucked
if he didn't say anything.
[cell phone vibrating]
[coach] Keep it up. guys. Let's go!
Jesus!
What?
- Foley. what the fuck? Let's go.
- Hey. just... just hold on. okay?
What's up with you two?
Your sex tape get leaked?
Dude. Bryce...
He's missing.
So?
Well. he'll be back.
His mom pays. like. zero attention.
I'm sure he got drunk after Homecoming
and stayed drunk somewhere.
Yeah. Could be.
Now let's go. Foley.
We're putting in a nickel package
against East Cali.
[Ani] And have you talked to Jessica?
I mean. there's a whole story there.
All right. look.
Given how destructive and public
the events at the homecoming game were.
we're looking at
a multiple-day suspension.
- Okay.
- And I understand that
there are some very strong feelings here
and you and your group have
an important voice that needs to be heard.
and I want to be sensitive to that.
But I also want to find a solution
- that is positive. even...
- [cell vibrating]
progressive. as well as remedial.
- Oh. shit!
- I'm sorry?
I mean...
Yeah. Yeah. yeah. whatever.
If I suspend you.
I have to suspend everybody in your group.
Not to mention Clay Jensen
and Tyler Down.
As well as the majority
of the football team:
Zach Dempsey. Justin Foley.
Charlie Saint-George.
Montgomery de la Cruz...
Wouldn't that be a shame.
if Monty got suspended?
We have damage to our stadium
and to our field.
We had to cancel the homecoming dance.
I have football players walking around
with black eyes and bloody faces
- like they've been through the wars.
- Isn't that what football's all about?
I have the Dean of Students
of Hillcrest calling
threatening personal injury lawsuits.
Well. they started it.
Our students threw all the first punches.
Yeah. but Hillcrest started it.
You get that. right?
This was about Bryce Walker. was it not?
The fact that he was on the field.
- Bryce Walker had nothing to do with it.
- Yeah.
Well. you and I both know that's not true.
Now. you listen to me. Jessica.
you incited a riot
and there are consequences.
You're the Student Body President.
for Christ's sake.
you're supposed to be a role model!
That's what I was being.
[Clay] We're going to Monet's.
to talk about Bryce.
- And?
- And...
- we need you.
- Why?
Well. we always need you.
- Aren't you worried about it?
- Why would I be?
Tyler. that's a thing I gotta worry about.
Bryce means nothing to me.
Can you give us a ride to Monet's?
[Ani] Tony Padilla.
also a secret-keeper...
[Tony] I don't care about Bryce.
I hope he stays gone.
[Clay] I don't think it's good
for either of us if he does.
Any of us.
What makes you say that?
I mean. if they start digging.
Spring Fling and everything.
[Tony] Bryce Walker has been no part
of my life for a long time.
and my life has been better for it.
I'm at peace.
[Ani] Especially for Clay.
Okay. Tyler. We're gonna drive you home.
We're gonna go inside with you.
Whatever happens. it's gonna...
It's gonna be okay.
I don't have my keys.
Oh. right...
Here.
[gasps]
Tyler! Oh. Tyler.
[Tyler's mom] You're okay.
Oh! We were so worried.
What happened to your head?
[stammers] He fell earlier.
We got the text
and then you weren't in your room.
We didn't even know
you'd gone to the dance.
- Sorry. Mrs. Down. There was a text?
- About the shooter.
We got the text
that the dance was being evacuated.
We couldn't find you.
Your father is down there now.
Um. do your parents know that you're okay?
- Yes.
- I should check in.
Okay. well. they must want you home
but you're welcome to spend the night.
If they'd have found this...
Do we...
tear it up?
I just...
I never thought I'd see my mom again.
But why tonight?
He just got back. I heard he was better.
Did something happen?
Where did the bruises come from?
We have to get him help.
But if anyone finds out why...
Then we're all fucked.
So...
So we'll figure it out.
We saved him. he's our responsibility.
[swallows]
Thanks for...
getting into this with me.
You're a good friend.
It's my blessing and my curse.
[Ani] I don't really know
how far Clay would go...
to protect a friend.
I went right up
to that little punk kid. Cyrus.
I was sure he was the one who called.
And I grabbed him and I started going off
and then.
Zach. like. ran up and was like.
"It was me. I called the cops.
Tyler should go to jail."
And so I told him
if Tyler goes to jail now.
so does Tony. and so does Clay.
at least.
And that stopped him?
That's when the cops
started coming through the front
and they shut the music down and started
getting everyone on the ground.
Me and Jess were right by Zach.
so I was like.
"You get to decide now
if you take down Clay and Tony.
and probably me and Jess with Tyler.
- and fuck up this school even more.
- [cell vibrating]
or if we get out of this."
Well...
everyone's coming.
I'm buying.
- It's really good to see you today.
- Oh. no. No!
What happened last night
was a one-time thing
and it's never happening again.
understand?
Jess. shit... I'm sorry.
I don't need your apology.
And stop giving me
that fucking puppy dog eye look.
It does not work on me
and it never actually did.
- I'm sorry.
- If you apologize again. I will cut you.
- [Alex] Why are you cutting him?
- Um...
Because he's evil.
- Good morning.
- Hey.
- You look really cute.
- Do I? Thank you.
[Justin] We went over to roll his car
into a parking place.
We figured we could hide it
with other cars.
But the keys were still in it...
Tyler didn't plan on coming back to it.
- So. I drove it away.
- [Cyrus] Jesus.
That's balls.
[Zach] It was fucking stupid.
going out there.
stepping in front of a gun like that.
acting like a fucking hero or something.
You called the cops.
I passed the cops on my way out.
Think about that timing!
If I hadn't done something.
kids would be dead!
We don't know that.
All you did was give Tyler another chance.
- Exactly.
- Another chance to do it again.
What if no one stops him next time?
We make sure there isn't a next time.
That's insane. Clay!
He needs serious help.
We can get him help.
But if we tell anyone what he did.
then he's expelled at least
and probably in jail.
and probably tried as an adult.
So. he's in juvie until he's 21.
and then they send him to prison
and then what happens to him?
No...
This is bullshit.
- I'm out.
- Zach...
I won't tell. I won't say anything.
but it's just not my job
to take care of that psychopath.
[Ani] Clay and his friends...
they kept it close.
I wasn't really part of the group.
Dude. what the actual fuck? Do they really
think something happened to Bryce?
I don't think they know.
I mean. it's possible
he's just at some hotel in Vegas. right?
I just. I...
If they start looking into shit.
between me and Bryce.
between you. me and Bryce.
like that night at his house last spring.
[manager] Justin.
wanna maybe bus a few tables
while you're out there.
- at least pretend you actually work here.
- Yeah. sorry.
I gotta start my shift.
What night at his house last spring?
Does Justin seem...
freaked out?
Aren't you?
You don't have to worry about me. okay?
I can take care of myself.
Hey. Alex.
- Hey. did anyone text you?
- No. Why?
Oh. shit.
Sorry. I forgot you weren't
on the chain. It wasn't about you.
Um...
What was it about then?
I guess Bryce Walker is missing.
What does that mean?
It means no one's seen him
since Friday night.
But. like. do they think
something happened to him?
I mean. who knows?
Look. Justin has work
and Clay is still downtown.
- so Cyrus said he'd give you a ride home.
- Oh. okay.
- Is that not okay?
- No. it's great.
[stammers] I just...
He's probably not happy about it. right?
Look. my mom's coming to get me later.
Do you want to wait with me?
- Would that be okay?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Out front at five.
Okay.
[zipping]
[Ani] When Bryce went missing. at first.
we all figured he'd show up in time.
We weren't really that worried about it.
I've missed the carriage house.
Justin and I prefer "outhouse."
Well. you two have done
some more decorating.
We've not.
Well. that wasn't there before.
Or that.
That's not decorating.
that's putting shit up.
I apologize.
I should have used a more manly verb.
I'm just saying.
You are good at so many things.
but one of your greatest gifts
is staying angry.
I'm not angry with you.
And self-awareness. not one of your gifts.
I know myself just fine. I spend more time
in my own head than anywhere else.
[scoffs] Breaking news!
He's just gonna turn up. right?
- Bryce?
- And what if he doesn't?
And what if they find out
what happened at Homecoming?
- So I lay low for a while.
- Clay. they arrested you.
- Not yet. they just questioned me.
- Because they think you did something.
- I didn't.
- Then shouldn't we find out who did?
How did Bryce get my bike lock?
[door opening]
Day-old pastries.
I got us the Monday mother lode. Hey. Ani.
[Justin groaning]
[Justin] I have lemon bars. pound cake.
scones so dry
they taste like you're eating a wall.
- Oh. I love those.
- [Justin] Mmm.
- I need some air.
- Clay...
[whispering in Swahili]
[door closing]
Fucking hate when you guys speak African.
Eh. you are aware that Africa is
an entire continent. yeah?
- Yeah. I'm aware. Eat these.
- Hmm.
[knock on door]
- Hey. buddy.
- Hey. Dad.
You got a minute?
I want to talk to you
about some developments today.
- Yeah.
- So... [sighing]
Bryce Walker's missing.
He hasn't been seen since
after the homecoming game Friday night.
Oh. wow.
- And Clay Jensen already told you.
- Yeah.
Right. So. have you heard anything?
Heard from Bryce?
No. I mean.
I saw him real quick at the game.
- but that was before it even started.
- All right.
Didn't you two spend some time together
this past summer?
Oh. I mean...
a little. Not really.
I mean. it was a while ago.
All right. Well. you know.
if you hear anything.
We're hoping this kid's just missing
but his window's closing fast.
Yeah. I'll let you know. Dad.
If I hear anything.
All right.
Hmm.
[sighs]
[Ani] Where was Bryce?
Had something happened?
Did it have anything to do
with the secrets Clay Jensen had kept
since that day last spring?
Yeah. it was a whole thing.
At least you're all safe.
It sounds like it was an overreaction.
Okay. here you go. Justin.
- So. the social worker visits a few times.
- [message alert]
They process the paperwork.
then they'll schedule the custody hearing
once everything's been filed
and they've confirmed
that they can't contact your mother.
Okay. Got it.
Hey. I think we should
clear out the workshop.
- Turn it into a bedroom.
- For Justin?
So we bring him into the house
then send him to a different building?
For both boys.
They're going to be seniors next year.
- They need their space.
- [Clay's mom] Apparently.
they don't need their space.
as they manage all kinds
of miscreant behavior without us knowing.
Right. Clay?
Clay?
Uh. right.
[message alert]
- Good morning. Tony.
- Morning.
- Thanks for giving Tyler a ride.
- It's my pleasure.
- You have a good one. Mrs. Down.
- You too.
Bye.
It's not really your pleasure.
To drive me.
Yeah. it is.
I help my friends.
I'm not your friend.
Yeah. you are.
Well. you're Clay's friend. clearly. so...
you're mine.
You think everyone will keep it secret?
I do.
We're all in this together.
Who called the police?
We don't know.
[Ani] Even knowing nothing.
I could tell Clay had a lot going on.
A lot to take care of.
[Monty] Hey. Tyler. What's up?
[stammering] I can't... I can't do this.
I've got to go.
Fuck that guy. He's not gonna hurt you.
No one's gonna push you around anymore.
- I can't.
- Tyler. it's okay.
[Tony] Okay. Tyler.
I need you to listen to me. okay?
Focus on your breathing. Hey.
Breathe as deep as you can.
[exhales deeply]
Look. you have first with Alex. right?
Stick with Alex. he'll walk you to second.
Me and Justin will meet you at lunch.
Okay. Okay.
Something happened to that kid.
He's not right.
You think Monty...
Well. Monty. Bryce. Jamie Garrison.
the kid gets it from fucking everywhere.
There's no way this is gonna work.
- It has to.
- Are you guys sure you got all his guns?
[Ani] The whole school was wired. on edge.
There will be an active shooter drill
some time in the next two weeks.
We will not be told in advance.
We don't want to add to anyone's anxiety
after Saturday's false alarm.
Clay Jensen.
Principal Bolan.
- Hey. Clay.
- Hey. Courtney.
- Sorry to pull you out of class.
- I thought it was Principal Bolan.
I just used one of his slips.
It's our turn for the new student tour.
I have an appointment
in the careers center
and the Wellesley recruiter's
only here for a day. So. can you take it?
Thank you! Thank you.
Ani. it was nice to meet you.
- You too. Bye.
- Goodbye. Thank you.
You gotta be fucking kidding me?
I don't really need a tour.
[Clay] This is the trophy case.
And we actually have many more
academic decathlon and robotics trophies.
but they're kept
in the math and science wing.
which is in a different building
to keep the main student body
from being infected
by something like actual knowledge.
To your left is the classroom
of the ironically named Mr. Champion.
who stares at girls' breasts
while he's talking to them.
These are posters for the drama club.
We actually have
the most low-key drama club anywhere.
They're totally not annoying people
at all.
The drawback being
their plays are super boring. but
really nice people
Library's out that way.
It's a pretty typical library
as high school libraries go.
which means underfunded
and thoroughly devoid of any book
that could be remotely controversial.
This is my locker.
which I sometimes use
to stick my head into and scream.
What the fuck?
Hey. leave him the fuck alone!
Hey. I need you to step off
and leave him alone. got it?
Dude. that's my brother.
Oh. Um...
Well. so the fuck what?
You should still leave him alone.
Brothers should take care of each other.
I told him no coffee before the tour.
but...
They call this the back quad.
even though there's no front quad
and back quad sounds like "backwad."
which sounds either like a wedgie
or a roll of fat that shows
when your shirt rides up.
Football and soccer field down there.
baseball field out there.
Clearly the nicest parts of the school.
because athletes are our heroes
and deserving of everything they want.
including the ability
to sexually assault girls
and never suffer any sort of consequences.
because why should they?
Um...
Sorry.
Cafeteria over there. I bring my lunch.
That's not a commentary
on the cafeteria food.
that's just a nugget from my life.
Wow.
I've been to. like. five high schools
in three years.
and that is by far the worst tour
I've ever been given.
The absolute worst.
[sighs] I'm sorry.
It's kind of a weird time here.
That's quite all right.
It's also. like. my favorite tour ever.
Well...
thanks.
[Ani] He gave me a tour.
Just a boring tour.
I didn't really talk to him after.
Hey. You don't mind if I join. do you?
I feel like you're obligated
to be nice to me.
- at least for the rest of the day.
- Because you're new?
Or because on my tour
you assaulted a guy.
Ah...
sure. have a seat.
Hi. Ani.
- Tyler.
- It's a pleasure. Tyler.
So. tell me about Clay.
He internalizes. doesn't he?
Oh. I mean. I don't...
You literally just met me.
How would you know that?
Hey.
Justin. Ani. Ani. Justin.
Pleasure.
You know. for a sour puss.
you have loads of friends.
Tyler is my friend.
Justin lives with me and my family.
They're adopting me.
Oh. that's fantastic.
Clay believes brothers should
take care of each other.
I need... ketchup.
[clears throat]
So. he might seem like an uptight asshole
at first. maybe even for a while.
but...
he's a really good guy.
so just give him some time. He's worth it.
How much time?
Hmm.
For me. it took. like. eight years. but...
[Ani] I thought Clay was funny.
but not much beyond that.
His friend Jessica was more interesting.
[Courtney] Principal Bolan is just asking
that we do something.
[Jess] He just wants an excuse
to celebrate the damn athletes again.
[Courtney] It's been a difficult time
for the whole school.
[Jess] It's complete and total bullshit.
[Courtney] So. in light
of the stressful events.
Principal Bolan wants us to come up
with some ideas to promote school unity.
Oh. that's fucking ridiculous
and you know it. Courtney.
Can the secretary please strike "fucking"
from the record?
I don't really actually take notes.
but okay.
[Jess] I mean.
why are we even talking about unity?
That's just. like. the administration
wanting us to sit down and shut up
and not burn any more baseball fields.
We don't need more school spirit.
we need actual change.
- Right?
- Preach.
[Jess] I mean. people are just done.
We're pissed off.
And athletes are the problem.
Jess. you're a cheerleader.
I used to be a cheerleader.
- Guys. please.
- [boy] Everyone blames the athletes.
- [Jess] Athletes are the cause...
- Guys!
- The cause of everything? That's bull!
- [Jess] Yes. everything!
- [boy] Yeah. you can't...
- Hey!
- [Jess] You're bullies and...
- Stop banging the hammer!
It's called a gavel!
The bullying. the harassment.
you guys are always the root of it.
And you guys never deal
with any of the consequences.
Look. Jessica.
I am super sympathetic to your feelings.
All right?
Especially given the circumstances
under which I ascended to president.
e.g. the ouster of Marcus.
the sexist pig who likes strippers.
That being said.
the student council has no actual power
and student councils as a rule never do.
And like most. I actually just did it
for my college applications.
So. if you really want
to stir some shit up
and make this student council more
than just a joke.
you should run for next year's president.
okay?
New business. please.
[girl] Graduation is only 46 days away
and Principal Bolan wants us
to recruit underclassmen.
I think you should do it.
I think you're primed to explode
in good ways.
I can tell things about people.
Hey. new girl.
Oh. Ani Achola.
What do you mean I'm primed to explode?
Oh. shit. I meant no offense.
I just meant...
well. I look at you
and I see you're bad-arse.
And you just walk up to people
and say shit like that?
Uh...
I do.
[laughs]
It's a bad habit I got in
while always being the new girl and
not doing the shy thing.
I pick the interesting people
and I make them friends.
Speaking of which. I can be
your campaign manager. if you like.
You want to be my...
Wait. what?
I've seen girls like you before and...
I want to help you be heard.
And you can help me with things.
like finding the robotics lab.
You like robots?
Yeah.
Cool.
It's in the main hall. at the end.
- Thanks.
- Campaign strategy meeting tomorrow.
After school.
Hey...
What do you mean. girls like me?
Who've got power
they're finally ready to use.
[Ani] I met a few friends at school.
And then. Bryce Walker came into my life.
[sobbing]
Um...
- hello?
- Hi.
Can I help you with something?
I'm just waiting for my mom to get home.
Your mum is Mrs. Walker?
My mom is Mrs. Walker. yeah.
Oh.
[laughs]
- [laughs]
- Wow.
And if I may. who are you?
Sorry. Ani.
My mum is your grandfather's nurse.
Ani.
It's nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you...
- Bryce.
My mother never mentioned me?
Oh. no. No. I'm sure she did.
- We've only been here a week or so.
- Yeah. Got it.
I got home from Hillcrest today
and the house was full of fucking movers.
packing up all the personal shit.
all my shit.
Bryce. language. Please.
He left me a note.
On actual paper.
I assume he went to the new house
in Telluride?
You know about that?
I'm divorcing him.
I know about everything.
Yeah. Yeah. he moved with that woman
to Telluride.
And he told me to come live here.
I've been calling him for hours.
He won't pick up.
I'm sure.
So...
surprise!
I'll have a room made up for you.
So. is Grandpa. like...
How's Grandpa?
Dying.
But slowly. So. that's nice.
Mom. is this okay?
Me being here.
It'll have to be. won't it?
[Ani's mum] Any news?
There isn't.
Still missing.
Let me see to dinner.
Some of those children...
hated him so much.
I imagine any number of them
might have wanted to hurt him.
But why now?
There's just something about
that whole mess at the Liberty Homecoming.
Was it that Jessica Davies?
That boy. Clay Jensen?
[Ani's mum] I pray no one has hurt him.
Mrs. Walker. He's a good boy.
Oh...
Well...
No. he isn't.
Was Ani at Homecoming?
- [Mrs. Walker] Friday night?
- [Ani's mum] No.
[Ani's mum] No.
[Ani] Bryce Walker came into my life.
and my life got complicated.
And here's the thing.
I know the Bryce that no one else knows.
Sorry.
Oh. your mum said I should use the pool
whenever I...
That's cool.
Don't let me stop you.
[Tony] I'm not worried
about the cops. Caleb.
- They're asking all sorts of questions.
- Well. let them ask.
What more can they do to me
at this point?
- What more can they take away?
- I'm thinking a lot.
They're not going to be interested
in me.
You're a person of color in the life
of a white kid who went missing
in a small town.
They're interested.
Well. you're a person of color
in his life. too. aren't you?
What are you obsessing over?
Homecoming.
Like. everyone posted pictures of it.
Do you remember anything...
from the game
or everything that happened after?
Anything that might tell us
where Bryce went?
Not really. We talked some shit
during the game.
but I didn't really see him
once shit got crazy.
Where'd you get those?
I got them from Tyler.
He had his camera that night.
Wait. Zoom in on that last one.
That's Zach.
[Clay] And that's Bryce tackling him.
[Justin] But he said it was number 82
who did it.
the big-ass defensive end on Hillcrest.
When we were helping Zach off the field.
he said it was 82.
This morning he told me
he didn't know who did it.
Why would he lie about that?
[Ani] So. yes...
I know all the players.
I know all the secrets.
["Severed" playing]
Bryce. Dude. it's me.
Where the hell are you?
♪ I alight like a whisper ♪
[cell message] Tyler. it's Bryce. Walker.
Listen. that thing we talked about.
I'm dealing with it.
You're all good.
Take care of yourself. man.
♪ I'm allied to the winter ♪
[Ani] The stories
that you think you know...
♪ Don't you get clever ♪
[Ani] ...and the ones
that have yet to be told.
♪ Don't you get clever ♪
[Ani] ...I know how they all connect.
♪ I'm allied to the landslide ♪
♪ Gonna leave you all severed ♪
♪ I alone am the answer ♪
♪ I alone will make wrongs right ♪
♪ But in order to root out the cancer ♪
♪ It's got to be kept from the sunlight ♪
[Ani] We can go through it together.
And I bet we can figure out
exactly what happened.
Where it all went wrong.
- [Monty] Hey!
- [Standall] All right. all right. Relax.
How is it when my dad beats the shit out
of me. I'm the one who gets arrested?
You're not arrested.
we're just going to have a little chat.
Yeah. about what?
Bryce Walker.
♪ Gonna leave you all severed ♪
[Ani] And I'll tell you everything.
Settle in. This could take a while.
Fuck.
♪ Gonna leave you all severed ♪
♪ I'm allied to the winter ♪
[man] Well done. Ed. Well done.